Speaker 1 (higher-pitched voice): Mr. President, I want to thank the leader for his strong words about the importance of making sure that we advance our military leaders when they have been approved for promotion and pay increases. You know, most people are aware that the Senate votes
Woman 2: on nominees who have been appointed by the president to occupy top roles in almost all parts of the federal government.
Woman 2: cabinet secretaries, judges, ambassadors. Less well-known is the fact that the Senate must also vote to approve thousands of military promotions every year. So if a
Speaker 3 (higher-pitched voice): colonel has done well on the job and their services promotion board
Speaker 4 (higher-pitched voice): decides that they're ready to be a brigadier general,
The
Speaker 4 (higher-pitched voice): Senate must vote to approve this promotion before it can go through. Now, typically, this vote is a formality. These promotions are processed in big batches, rather than one at a time, and they usually
Speaker 5 (higher-pitched voice): happen without even taking a recorded vote. But right now, the Senator from Alabama has
Speaker 6 (higher-pitched voice): imposed a hold on all
Speaker 6 (higher-pitched voice): every single senior
Speaker 4 (higher-pitched voice): military nomination and promotion. That means that one senator is personally standing in the way of promotions for 184 of our top-level military
Speaker 7 (higher-pitched voice): leaders. One senator is holding up pay raises for men and women in uniform. One senator is blocking key senior military leaders from taking their posts.
Speaker 7 (higher-pitched voice): one senator is jeopardizing America's
Speaker 3 (higher-pitched voice): national security. Think for a minute about what this looks like. These holds deprive military families of the pay
Speaker 6 (higher-pitched voice): increases that they've earned because the nominee's new pay cannot take effect until the promotion goes through.
Speaker 1 (higher-pitched voice): Without formally being assigned to a change of duty, families can't make decisions
Woman 2: right now about moving or enrolling kids in a new school for next school year. The Chief of Staff of the Army has said, "What it really does, it affects the families and some of the kids, and they're trying to figure out where they're going to school, where they're going to move.
Woman 2: And all those things kind of come into the readiness of the force.
Speaker 3 (higher-pitched voice): For families with special needs, there may be even more significant delays to access important
Speaker 1 (higher-pitched voice): services. Secretary Austin has stated that this delay "creates a ripple effect through the force that makes us far less ready than we need
Speaker 7 (higher-pitched voice): to be."
So,
Speaker 7 (higher-pitched voice): why is one senator punishing 184 dedicated men and women who actively serve in our military? All because he personally disagrees with a single
Speaker 4 (higher-pitched voice): policy decision from the Pentagon.
Now
Speaker 4 (higher-pitched voice): look, it is no secret that I disagree with a lot of policy decisions from the Pentagon. And as senators, we have a lot of tools to shape
Speaker 7 (higher-pitched voice): and influence government policies. Tools that we can use without putting our national defense at risk. We
Speaker 3 (higher-pitched voice): can pass laws. We can conduct oversight. We can meet with administration officials. We can hold
Speaker 4 (higher-pitched voice): hearings.
Speaker 4 (higher-pitched voice): Occasionally, a senator may object to an individual nomination, usually to indicate
Speaker 7 (higher-pitched voice): opposition to that appointment or to insist on answers
Speaker 5 (higher-pitched voice): to questions from a federal agency. I've done this myself in the past, as have many of my colleagues on both sides of the aisle.
But that
Speaker 5 (higher-pitched voice): is not what the senator from Alabama is doing.
Speaker 5 (higher-pitched voice): Instead, he is blocking every single top military
Speaker 6 (higher-pitched voice): leader from advancing indefinitely. He has snared all 184 top-level service members who are currently slated for
Speaker 7 (higher-pitched voice): advancement and he has stopped every single one of them dead in their tracks. Like me, the senator from Alabama serves on the Senate Armed Services Committee.
Speaker 7 (higher-pitched voice): And as a consequence, he has many more opportunities than most senators to influence DOD policy. He has many more opportunities to question witnesses, many more opportunities to receive briefings, and many more opportunities to influence the annual defense bill that Congress passes every single year to govern Pentagon operations. He has many opportunities that do not actively threaten our
nation.
Speaker 7 (higher-pitched voice): He has not raised any individual objections to the 184 service members whose promotions are now held up
Speaker 4 (higher-pitched voice): in the Senate, and he has not raised any objections
Speaker 6 (higher-pitched voice): to the process by which these men and women were vetted and nominated.
Speaker 6 (higher-pitched voice): No, the senator is blocking 184 top
Speaker 4 (higher-pitched voice): military promotions because he disagrees with the Department of Defense policy to help service members and their families access needed health care, specifically to travel to access abortion care. Now, I disagree with the senator on that issue.
Speaker 4 (higher-pitched voice): But if he wants to press for votes to reverse DOD's health care policies, he can do that. I will oppose him, but if I lose and if Congress changes the law, then DOD will change its policies. That is how democracy works. Holding up the promotion of every single military nominee isn't democracy, it's
Speaker 7 (higher-pitched voice): extortion.
Speaker 7 (higher-pitched voice): And that kind of extortion has serious consequences for our national defense.
Speaker 3 (higher-pitched voice): These holds pose a grave threat to our national security and to our military readiness. They actively hurt our ability to respond quickly to threats around the world.
Just
Speaker 3 (higher-pitched voice): take a look at the list of 184 people who've already been approved for promotions.
Speaker 4 (higher-pitched voice): The 184 people that the senator from Alabama have blocked so far
Speaker 7 (higher-pitched voice): include nominations for the next commander of the U.S. 5th Fleet in the Middle East, nomination for the next commander of the 7th Fleet in the Pacific.
Speaker 7 (higher-pitched voice): Our next military representative to NATO and the current Director of
Speaker 6 (higher-pitched voice): Intelligence for U.S. Cyber Command. It includes our next Deputy Chief of Staff for Strategic Deterrence and Nuclear Integration for the Air Force. It includes a top official in Birmingham's Army Reserves. And it includes the former Chief of Staff for Operation Warp Speed.
Speaker 6 (higher-pitched voice): a program the senator from Alabama has repeatedly credited for saving millions of American lives. In fact, the senator from Alabama is single-handedly holding up 11 three-star commanders,
Speaker 3 (higher-pitched voice): three recipients of Silver Stars, and three Purple Heart recipients.
Speaker 3 (higher-pitched voice): These are brave service
Speaker 7 (higher-pitched voice): members who deserve better than to be stuck in an administrative hell waiting for a single senator to release them to
Speaker 4 (higher-pitched voice): the promotions and the assignments and the pay increases that
Speaker 1 (higher-pitched voice): their military leaders have determined that they have already earned.
The
Speaker 1 (higher-pitched voice): Department of Defense has warned that these blanket holds are making the United States more vulnerable
to
Speaker 6 (higher-pitched voice): threats from foreign
Speaker 5 (higher-pitched voice): actors like China, North Korea, and Iran.
In the
Speaker 5 (higher-pitched voice): coming months, approximately 80
Speaker 5 (higher-pitched voice): Three- and four-star
Speaker 6 (higher-pitched voice): generals and admirals, including the leaders of the Army, Navy, and Marine Corps, will reach the end of their current terms, and new nominees will be slotted to replace them. In addition, if the Senator's reckless hold is not lifted, and if the Senate cannot confirm a new chair of the Joint Chiefs of Staff,
Speaker 6 (higher-pitched voice): the President may be without a principal military advisor. By the end of this year, we could have 650
Speaker 4 (higher-pitched voice): general and flag officers waiting for Senate confirmation.
The Senator
Speaker 4 (higher-pitched voice): from Alabama's response to his actions is to say that he will keep these holds in place,
quote,
Speaker 4 (higher-pitched voice): until hell freezes over, unless DOD changes its health care travel policy.
Speaker 6 (higher-pitched voice): I sincerely hope that is not true, because holding hostage nearly
Speaker 3 (higher-pitched voice): the entire military leadership of the United States of America at a time when we are facing military threats around the world and our allies are literally engaged in war in Europe is dangerous.
Speaker 3 (higher-pitched voice): It is reckless and it needs to stop
Speaker 4 (higher-pitched voice): right now. As chair of the Senate Armed Services Subcommittee on Personnel, I care deeply about protecting our service members and the integrity of our promotion system. These holds are depriving families of pay
raises
Speaker 6 (higher-pitched voice): that they have earned.
Speaker 6 (higher-pitched voice): We're talking about grocery money for families.
Speaker 7 (higher-pitched voice): These service members are being treated disrespectfully, people who should be treated with dignity and respect. And unless there is some specific problem with an individual nominee, those who have
Speaker 4 (higher-pitched voice): been nominated for a new rank or a new post should get the advancement that the Pentagon
Speaker 6 (higher-pitched voice): has already recommended for them. No more politics.
I am
Speaker 6 (higher-pitched voice): here today to respectfully ask my colleague from Alabama to let these promotions move forward
Speaker 4 (higher-pitched voice): and to find other ways to continue advocating for the policy changes that he wants to see. I am hopeful that he will set aside politics and do what is the right thing and allow these service members to carry out their
Speaker 6 (higher-pitched voice): responsibilities to our nation.